amexnetwork.com 2008-12-17

# The American Express Network > Privacy Policy

### Internet Privacy Statement for AmexNetwork.com

This Privacy Statement describes the information practices of this website, AmexNetwork.com ("our site" or "the website"). AmexNetwork.com is a place for consumers to find out more about special features available for cardmembers holding American Express-branded cards, including American Express-branded cards issued by American Express entities and entities other than American Express. The website is a resource for cardmembers to find out about unique experiences, special insights, and cardmember promotions and benefits, and is administered and maintained by the Global Merchant Network Group unit ("GMNG," "we," or "us") of American Express Travel Related Services Company, Inc., the unit responsible for operating the network through which merchants accept American Express-branded cards. AmexNetwork.com respects your privacy and is committed to protecting it at all times. This Privacy Statement applies only to our U.S. cardmembers and U.S. visitors to AmexNetwork.com, and explains how we collect, use, disclose and safeguard information. AmexNetwork.com reserves the right to change this Privacy Statement at any time by posting revisions on this page. Such changes will be effective upon posting.

### Customer Service

For any questions about your American Express-branded card account, please call the number on the back of your card.

Click here to learn:

What Information We Collect and How We Use It  
Choosing How We Market To You  
How We Safeguard Personal Information  
How You Can Access and Change Personal Information   

### What Information We Collect and How We Use It

Use of Cookies or Similar Technologies on Our Website  
Personal Information We Collect on Our Website  
How We Use and Share Personal Information  
Ads That Link to Our Website

**Use of Cookies or Similar Technologies on Our Website**  
When you visit our website, we collect information in order to service your accounts, save you time and better respond to your needs. A "cookie" is a small piece of information that a website transfers to the hard drive of a visitor's computer for record-keeping purposes. Traditional browser based cookies or a Flash cookie (Shared Object) may be used. We use "[cookie](http://www10.americanexpress.com/sif/cda/component/0,,128685,00.asp#C)" technology to collect site statistical information and improve your customer experience. They provide visitors a personalized experience on our site by enabling us to determine unique preferences and trends based on visits to our website and to other websites. However, none of this information is associated with you as an individual and is measured only in aggregate. Cookies set by the American Express Network do not capture any personally identifiable information, such as your individual e-mail address. 

We also automatically collect some statistical data as you browse this website. For example, we automatically collect a number that is assigned to your computer automatically and required for using the Internet (your "[IP address](http://www10.americanexpress.com/sif/cda/component/0,,128685,00.asp#IA)"), which is used to connect your computer to the Internet, browser type and version, operating system and platform, average time spent on our site, pages viewed, information searched for, access times, information that users generate as they move from page to page and click on items within a website ("clickstream data"), and other relevant information about your online experience. Note that clickstream data is usually stored in log files and Website designers use it to improve users' experiences with a site.

You may browse our Website anonymously by choosing not to provide us with any "[personally identifiable information (PII)](http://www10.americanexpress.com/sif/cda/component/0,,128685,00.asp#PII)," or by choosing not to register during your visits to our sites. PII is individually identifiable data about a consumer collected online from you and maintained by us, including name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, any other identifier that permits the physical or online contacting of an individual, and information collected from the user in combination with another identifier. When you browse this way, we will not link your online activity with the accounts you may have with us. 

The American Express Network may use "[Web beacons](http://www10.americanexpress.com/sif/cda/component/0,,128685,00.asp#WB)" to present offers on AmexNetwork.com, other sites on which The American Express Network advertises, or in our e-mails. Web beacons, also known as "clear GIFs" (a common format for image files), are invisible files located on webpages that you visit. They are often used in combination with a "cookie" to track navigation of a site. If you visit a page on AmexNetwork.com that contains a Web beacon, it communicates with your computer to determine, among other things, whether you have been to that page before or viewed a particular advertisement. This enables us to enhance e-mail offers and track website usage. We sometimes use entities that performs business operations on behalf of the American Express Network, such as: statement printing, mailing services, data processing, customer servicing, or collections ("[vendors](http://www10.americanexpress.com/sif/cda/component/0,,128685,00.asp#V)") and or merchants with whom we conduct transactions on your behalf, co-marketers, and providers of loyalty campaigns ("[business partners](http://www10.americanexpress.com/sif/cda/component/0,,128685,00.asp#BP)") to manage web beacons and the data they collect; however, Web beacons do not capture your individual e-mail address or any other personal information that you enter on the the American Express Network website. 

Web beacons are sometimes used on AmexNetwork.com webpages where transactions take place. In addition, e-mail offers that we send may contain web beacons to help us record response rates and to assist us in measuring the offer's effectiveness.

Back to top

**Personal Information We Collect on Our Website**  
If you enroll in online products or services provided on AmexNetwork.com, you may provide us with personal information such as your name, address, e-mail address, card account number and telephone number. Depending on the online service in which you choose to enroll, you may provide additional information such as your travel preferences.

Back to top

**How We Use and Share Personal Information**  
We may use personal information collected from you and provided by you, together with information we have about you as an American Express-branded cardmember, publicly available information, and preferences you indicate on our site to authenticate you as a cardmember, process transactions you conduct on our website, verify your status as an American Express cardmember, conduct internal analyses, customize your experience (such as providing you with exclusive access to cardmember only offers and customizing your website experience according to preferences you define around dining, travel, offers and other categories, fulfill special offers, respond to your requests, notify you of promotions, updates, or special offers that we think may interest you, provide you with a more effective experience while on our website, and to provide the products and services you enroll in or apply for. We may also use your personal information to facilitate offer redemptions in the form of a credit to your card statement. To do this, it is often necessary to share this information with carefully selected vendors and business partners we work with, such as the issuer of your American Express-branded card, companies that manage accounts, offer affinity, frequent-user, and reward programs, and companies that perform marketing services and other business operations for AmexNetwork.com. AmexNetwork.com does not share your personal information with third parties who may want to market to you their own products and services. To the extent permitted by law, we may disclose personal information to government authorities or third parties pursuant to a legal request, subpoena, or other legal process, or to help prevent fraud or any other crime.

Mobile Offers

The American Express Network does not sell or share mobile phone numbers with third parties and will only use the information for the specific communication into which you have opted-in.

Back to top

**Ads That Link to Our Website**  
We hire other companies to place banner ads on other websites and to perform tracking and reporting activities ("third-party advertisement servers"). They do not collect personal information in doing this work for us, and we do not give any personal information to them. 

Third-party advertisement servers are subject to their own privacy policies. If you would like more information about the privacy policies of these third-party advertisement servers, including information on how to opt out of their tracking methods, please click here to visit the Network Advertising Initiative website. 

Back to top

### Choosing How We Market To You

How We Use Your E-mail Address  
How to Opt Out of E-mail Marketing Offers  
Your Other Opt Out Choices 

**How We Use Your E-mail Address**  
We may use your e-mail address to send you the following types of e-mail messages: 

  * Occasional Updates and Valuable Offers. We may send you e-mail updates, reminders or regularly scheduled e-mail newsletters about products and services available on AmexNetwork.com. 
  * Service or confirmation notifications related to your transaction(s). 

To make our e-mail offers more relevant to you, we may use information you provided in your initial transaction with us, in surveys, from information we have about you as a holder of an American Express-branded card - such as purchasing preferences or lifestyle - and information available from external sources such as census bureau data. 

When we send e-mail to you, we may be able to identify information about your e-mail address, such as whether you can view graphic-rich HTML e-mail. If your e-mail address is HTML-enabled, we may choose to send you graphic-rich HTML e-mail messages.

Any email address provided for Remind Me messages will not be used for any purpose other than sending the email(s) and the email address will not be retained after the email(s) is sent.

You may also receive e-mail offers from the issuer of your American Express-branded card, or other companies, if you have requested that the company send you offers from its partners and/or advertisers. To decline offers from other companies who may send offers on behalf of the issuer of your American Express-branded cards, follow the instructions provided by that company. 

Back to top

**How to Opt Out of E-mail Marketing Offers**  
To opt out of receiving e-mail offers or newsletters from The American Express Network, click here. All e-mail offers and e-mail newsletters sent to you by us provide instructions on how to opt out of receiving future offers or newsletters. These instructions are located at the bottom of the e-mail message. You may receive separate newsletters pertaining to different products and services from the issuer of your American Express-branded card. In that case, you must reply to and decline the newsletters individually. If you opt out, we will still send you e-mail with service updates as well as other important information related to AmexNetwork.com's online products or services for which you have signed up. 

Back to top

**Opt Out Choices When Opting Out from the Issuer of Your American Express-Branded Card**  
If you are enrolled in one or more personal financial products from the issuer of your American Express-branded card, please call the Customer Service number provided by your issuer.

Back to top

### How We Safeguard Information

**We use reasonable administrative, technical and physical measures to safeguard your personal information.**

Site Security Features  
Selected Business Partners  
Linking to Other Internet Sites

**Site Security Features**  
_SSL Technology and how you benefit from it_  
We realize how important security is to you, so we've taken a number of steps to enhance the protection of personal information sent to or from our site over the internet. This includes Card and other account information. First, we require that a "secure session" be established, using Secure Socket Layer (SSL) Technology. This is done any time you supply or access personal information in one of our secure online areas. 

SSL Technology creates a private conversation that only your computer and our site can understand. The SSL Technology encodes information as it is being sent over the internet between your computer and our site, helping to ensure that the transmitted information remains confidential.

The use of SSL requires two components: an SSL-compatible browser and a Web server to perform the "key-exchange" that establishes a secure connection to The American Express Network Web server systems.

The technological requirements needed to benefit from SSL Technology:

  1. A Compliant Browser  
In order to securely access your personal information via the internet, you will need a browser with SSL capabilities. We recommend you use the latest browser versions available to ensure you have a browser with SSL capabilities. Examples of SSL browsers include Netscape 2.0 and above, Microsoft's Internet Explorer 2.0 and above, and the Web browser for America Online version 3.0 for Windows and above. (Note that some older versions of browsers will not support SSL sessions and some older versions of browsers are not JavaScript-enabled, which means that you may not be able to view all the features on the website). If you don't already have a JavaScript-enabled browser with SSL capabilities, you can download an SSL and JavaScript-enabled browser from any of the links below. 

  2. A Compliant Internet Service Provider  
Nearly all Internet Service Providers (ISPs) automatically enable the SSL session described above. If you use your company's internal connection to access the internet and you find you cannot access the secure pages on our site with an SSL browser described above, your company may be blocking access via a "firewall." Please speak to your firm's internet access systems administrator for further details on your network's internet access. 
  3. Enabled Cookies  
You also must have enabled cookies on your browser in order to access personal information. If you have chosen to disable cookies on your browser, you will not be able to access your personal information. 

_User ID and Password_  
Some areas of our site may require the use of a User ID and Password as an additional security measure that helps protect your personal information. This allows us to verify who you are, thereby allowing you access to your account information, and preventing unauthorized access. When you log off such an area, make sure you always click on the red "Exit Secure Area" or "Log Out" link which appears on the left-hand side of every secure page. When you click on it, you will be given the option to end your secure session. No further secure transactions can be conducted without re-entering your User ID and Password. 

_Services_  
This section is where you load on your information, e.g. name, address, email address You should be aware that browser software often "caches" a page as you look at it, meaning that some pages are saved in your computer's temporary memory. Therefore, you may find that clicking on your "Back" button shows you a saved version of a previously viewed page. Caching in no way affects the security of your confidential User ID or Password. If you use a computer in a public place to access your account information, simply quit/exit the browser software before leaving to minimize the possibility of anyone else viewing your personal information. 

Back to top

**Selected Business Partners**  
In order to bring you the many online products and services offered on AmexNetwork.com, we work with carefully selected vendors and business partners. If we have to share any information with these companies in order to provide a product or service to you, we first conduct a careful evaluation of their information and security systems and practices, and require reasonable administrative, technical, and physical measures to safeguard the personal information of holders of American Express-branded cards. We may audit our partners and vendors to verify the continued security of their systems and practices. 

Back to top

**Linking to Other Internet Sites**  
You should be aware that other internet sites that you link to from the website or The American Express Network e-mail may contain privacy provisions that differ from the provisions of our Privacy Statement. To ensure your privacy is protected, we recommend that you review the privacy statements of other internet sites you visit.

Back to top

### How You Can Access and Change Information

In order to review, update or delete your personal information submitted to this site, log in to access that online service. You may review, update or delete your e-mail marketing preferences about e-mail offers and newsletters from our site, including messages about our business partners' products. Click here to make any changes to your e-mail marketing preferences. While we will make reasonable efforts to accommodate your request to access your personal information, we also reserve the right to impose certain restrictions and requirements on such access requests, if allowed or required by applicable laws. 

Back to top

Effective date: June 4, 2006
